<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recipes on Ted Brandston</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/</link><description>Recent content in Recipes on Ted Brandston</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 09:49:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Applesauce</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/applesauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/applesauce/</guid><description>During apple season our local market sells a wonderful variety of very fresh apples. They also sell &amp;ldquo;second quality&amp;rdquo; apples in big boxes at a discount. At this time of year I like to make a bunch of applesauce, and freeze most of it for the winter and spring.
Of course I&amp;rsquo;ve got my weird ideas about how to best make applesauce. I like to add pears because I think it adds a nice slightly-floral element.</description></item><item><title>Late Night Snack</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/late-night-snack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/late-night-snack/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s late.
You ate dinner and put the kids to bed 3 hours ago, and now it&amp;rsquo;s almost bedtime but you&amp;rsquo;re hungry again.
Take a slice of bread Slather it with unsweetened peanut butter Pour a generous quantity of hot smoked paprika OR grind a generous quantity of black pepper onto the peanut butter Enjoy!</description></item><item><title>Sandy's Roasted Veggies</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/sandys-veggies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/sandys-veggies/</guid><description>At some point I was chatting with my neighbor, Mike, outside his house and caught a whiff of something basily and garlicky that smelled fantastic. I asked about it, and that evening Sandy, his wife &amp;amp; also our neighbor, dropped off a jar of roasted vegetables. They were as good as they smelled, and she gave me an approximate recipe. I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to quite replicate it, but my attempts have been pretty tasty.</description></item><item><title>Tuna Salad</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/tuna-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/tuna-salad/</guid><description>Ingredients:
1 can tuna in water 1 can sardines in olive oil Carrot, diced very small Celery, diced very small One small shallot, diced even smaller Capers in brine, some of which should be coarsely chopped Mayonnaise Dijon mustard Preparation:
Put tuna in a mixing bowl, reserving the water Add sardines, reserving the oil Add however much of the other ingredients you&amp;rsquo;d like. I generally start with: about a third of a cup each celery and carrot About a quarter cup of shallot About three tablespoons chopped capers, and another tablespoon whole A tablespoon each mayonnaise and mustard.</description></item><item><title>Two Tomato Soups</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/two-tomato-soups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/two-tomato-soups/</guid><description>The basic framework:
Put some tomatoes in a pot with seasonings Cook until thoroughly softened Lightly strain out the solids (and remove any large pieces of herb), reserving the juice Puree the solids to make a thick tomato soup (or base for pizza sauce) perfect for dunking grilled cheese into Use the juice as a broth for another soup For example: I put onions, garlic, fresh sage, and fresh rosemary, and olive oil in.</description></item></channel></rss>