<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ted Brandston</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Ted Brandston</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://tedbrandston.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>"How Things Usually Are" is not "How Things Should Be"</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/how-things-are-should-be/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/how-things-are-should-be/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have two small children, and it seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a certain age where they decide that how things usually are is how they should be. How they must be!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel like a classic example for this is &amp;ldquo;Boys don&amp;rsquo;t have long hair!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anonymity</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/anonymity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/anonymity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another significant Neverware memory is going over the company survey results. It was considered pretty important by most people that the submissions remain anonymous. A lot of the time that seemed fine, but sometimes it made very hard to make useful changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black &amp; White Cellular Automata</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/doodles/black-and-white-ca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/doodles/black-and-white-ca/</guid><description>Based on Cliff Biffle&amp;rsquo;s tremendously cool rust+webassembly series. This just flips through the various &amp;ldquo;1D&amp;rdquo; cellular automata you can make with two states and self+neighbor patterns, choosing from a few possible starting states. Most of &amp;rsquo;em end up not that interesting, but it was fun to practice my rust.</description></item><item><title>Bluest Eye</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/bluest-eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/bluest-eye/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had a moment today where a bunch of things all came together in my head and made a little mesh where they kind of supported each other. It was connecting things I remember thinking about after reading Toni Morrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Bluest_Eye">&lt;em>The Bluest Eye&lt;/em>&lt;/a> in high school with things I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking and reading more recently like &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23719305-how-emotions-are-made">&lt;em>How Emotions Are Made&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by Lisa Feldman Barrett.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Comments on This Website</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/comments-reasoning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/comments-reasoning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Comments online are hard. Moderating online conversations is hard. At the same time having that potential for interaction, for connection with other people, feels worth doing hard work for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how should comments work on this website?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Couples Inventory</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/couples-inventory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/couples-inventory/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every once in a while Kat and I do a &amp;ldquo;Couples Inventory&amp;rdquo;. Just a list of questions we ask, to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re addressing the things we need to be addressing. Kat proposed we start doing this shortly after we became parents, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s been really helpful. Here&amp;rsquo;s an edited version of that list:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Emotions are Made</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/sources/how-emotions-are-made/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/sources/how-emotions-are-made/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>How Emotions are Made: The Secret Life of the Brain&lt;/em> by Lisa Feldman Barrett (henceforth HEAM and LFB). This is a book that really changed how I perceive my experience of the world, and some of the concepts from it really seem to support concepts from other books that have made a big impression on me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Late Night Snack</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/late-night-snack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/late-night-snack/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s late.
You ate dinner and put the kids to bed 3 hours ago, and now it&amp;rsquo;s almost bedtime but you&amp;rsquo;re hungry again.
Take a slice of bread Slather it with unsweetened peanut butter Pour a generous quantity of hot smoked paprika OR grind a generous quantity of black pepper onto the peanut butter Enjoy!</description></item><item><title>Never Again</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/never-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/never-again/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I have been thinking about the tendency in organizations to say: &amp;ldquo;we can&amp;rsquo;t let this happen Ever Again.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My impression is that in most organizations there are moments when things happen, the result of those things is bad for the organization or the people in it, and so the organization says: &amp;ldquo;Never Again. We will put rules and processes in place to ensure that this Can&amp;rsquo;t Happen.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Productivity and Daily Planning</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/productivity-daily-planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/productivity-daily-planning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Productivity is something that I care about, and also something that I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure that productivity is the right word for what I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with: some mix of organization, choosing what to work on, finding time to work on it, and then working on the thing that I intended to work on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with both in work context and in a personal context, but recently I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve made some significant changes &amp;ndash; and one in particular &amp;ndash; that have really improved my ability to get things done at work (I&amp;rsquo;m still working on bringing this to my personal time). I might touch on some of the others, but the biggest improvement seems to come from planning out what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do at the beginning of each day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Respect</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/respect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/respect/</guid><description>&lt;p>During my time at Neverware I took a turn that has the director of engineering, and it really changed how I thought about the word &amp;ldquo;respect&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks on the leadership team used it pretty regularly, and at some point I took issue with it. The connotation I had for respect at that point (especially in a business setting) was &amp;ldquo;deference to authority&amp;rdquo;, and it sounded to me like what was being asked for was compliance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RGB Cellular Automata</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/doodles/rgb-ca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/doodles/rgb-ca/</guid><description>Based on Cliff Biffle&amp;rsquo;s tremendously cool rust+webassembly series, and continuing to riff on cellular automata, this uses three states instead of two. The extra state takes us from 23 = 8 &amp;ldquo;parent rules&amp;rdquo; and 28 = 256 rulesets, up to 33 = 27 &amp;ldquo;parent rules&amp;rdquo; with 327 = 7,625,597,484,987 rulesets!
I found that things got, visually, a little muddled with three colors, so I have it start out zoomed in on each one, so you can see the detail and patterns better, and then zoom out as it finishes calculating the image.</description></item><item><title>Sandy's Roasted Veggies</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/sandys-veggies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/sandys-veggies/</guid><description>At some point I was chatting with my neighbor, Mike, outside his house and caught a whiff of something basily and garlicky that smelled fantastic. I asked about it, and that evening Sandy, his wife &amp;amp; also our neighbor, dropped off a jar of roasted vegetables. They were as good as they smelled, and she gave me an approximate recipe. I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to quite replicate it, but my attempts have been pretty tasty.</description></item><item><title>Solar Biochar at Home</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/solar-biochar-at-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/solar-biochar-at-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>An idea: solar biochar at home&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A while back I read about &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biochar">biochar&lt;/a>. I think it was not-too-long after I attended &lt;a href="https://xiii.hope.net/">HOPE 2020&lt;/a>, and it felt like there were a few ideas floating around that pointed towards diverse, local approaches to climate change (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solarpunk">solarpunk&lt;/a> feels associated with this). I think it was also shortly before or after I read &lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/these-alternative-economies-are-inspirations-for-a-sustainable-world/">this article&lt;/a> in Scientific American, plus countless sources/articles looking at how adding carbon to soil can be a good method of carbon sequestration, while also improving crop yields and reducing disease in plants (which means less fertilizer and pesticide).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Primal Teen</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/sources/the-primal-teen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/sources/the-primal-teen/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>The Primal Teen: What The New Discoveries About The Teenage Brain Tell Us About Our Kids&lt;/em> by Barbara Strauch. I read this when I was too young (i.e. a teenager), and it messed me up pretty bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tuna Salad</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/tuna-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/tuna-salad/</guid><description>Ingredients:
1 can tuna in water 1 can sardines in olive oil Carrot, diced very small Celery, diced very small One small shallot, diced even smaller Capers in brine, some of which should be coarsely chopped Mayonnaise Dijon mustard Preparation:
Put tuna in a mixing bowl, reserving the water Add sardines, reserving the oil Add however much of the other ingredients you&amp;rsquo;d like. I generally start with: about a third of a cup each celery and carrot About a quarter cup of shallot About three tablespoons chopped capers, and another tablespoon whole A tablespoon each mayonnaise and mustard.</description></item><item><title>Two Tomato Soups</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/two-tomato-soups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/recipes/two-tomato-soups/</guid><description>The basic framework:
Put some tomatoes in a pot with seasonings Cook until thoroughly softened Lightly strain out the solids (and remove any large pieces of herb), reserving the juice Puree the solids to make a thick tomato soup (or base for pizza sauce) perfect for dunking grilled cheese into Use the juice as a broth for another soup For example: I put onions, garlic, fresh sage, and fresh rosemary, and olive oil in.</description></item><item><title>Waist Deep in the Big Muddy</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/waist-deep-in-the-big-muddy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/waist-deep-in-the-big-muddy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday, while Rosa and Juniper were in the bath, I put on &lt;em>Waist Deep in the Big Muddy and other Love Songs&lt;/em>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> by Pete Seeger. It&amp;rsquo;s an album I used to listen to on repeat when I was a little kid (my best guess is that I was somewhere in the 7 to 9 range), but I&amp;rsquo;ve only listened to it once or twice in the past 20 years and&amp;hellip; wow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting the songs/bits of songs I remember and those that I don&amp;rsquo;t. Most of the political messages went straight over my head.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We don't all interpret words the same ways</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/words/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think the last chapter of &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36739320-because-internet">&lt;em>Because Internet: Understanding the New Rules of Language&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by Gretchen McCulloch describes beautifully the way we each have our own, personal version of our languages, and what&amp;rsquo;s captured in the dictionary is more of an aggregate snapshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What she doesn&amp;rsquo;t get into is how many problems it can cause.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is Eco Friendly</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/what-is-eco-friendly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/what-is-eco-friendly/</guid><description>&lt;p>Writing about &lt;a href="https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/solar-biochar-at-home.md">a solar biochar kiln&lt;/a> left me thinking a lot about how to define &amp;ldquo;eco friendly&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been thinking about it in relation to some news a friend pointed me at: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2016/09/to-tote-or-note-to-tote/498557/">canvas&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/24/style/cotton-totes-climate-crisis.html">bags&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://qz.com/1585027/when-it-comes-to-climate-change-cotton-totes-might-be-worse-than-plastic/">are&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.euronews.com/green/2020/01/22/is-your-reusable-tote-worse-for-the-environment-than-a-plastic-bag">worse&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/sustainable-living/cotton-tote-bags-sustainable-shopping-b1909035.html">than&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.rateitgreen.com/green-building-community/discussions/plastic-vs-reusable-bags-which-bag-is-best/1340">plastic&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/579437/cotton-canvas-tote-bad-for-environment">bags&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/hFgtIziShmc">Poor Tim Minchin&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(I should note: I didn&amp;rsquo;t read all of those articles in full, most of them I skimmed. I know, I know, I know &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m part of the problem. They also mostly cite the same couple of studies. I might try to write more about that later&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>