<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>managerial-musings on Ted Brandston</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/tags/managerial-musings/</link><description>Recent content in managerial-musings on Ted Brandston</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://tedbrandston.github.io/tags/managerial-musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anonymity</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/anonymity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/anonymity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another significant Neverware memory is going over the company survey results. It was considered pretty important by most people that the submissions remain anonymous. A lot of the time that seemed fine, but sometimes it made very hard to make useful changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Never Again</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/never-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/never-again/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I have been thinking about the tendency in organizations to say: &amp;ldquo;we can&amp;rsquo;t let this happen Ever Again.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My impression is that in most organizations there are moments when things happen, the result of those things is bad for the organization or the people in it, and so the organization says: &amp;ldquo;Never Again. We will put rules and processes in place to ensure that this Can&amp;rsquo;t Happen.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Respect</title><link>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/respect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedbrandston.github.io/writing/respect/</guid><description>&lt;p>During my time at Neverware I took a turn that has the director of engineering, and it really changed how I thought about the word &amp;ldquo;respect&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks on the leadership team used it pretty regularly, and at some point I took issue with it. The connotation I had for respect at that point (especially in a business setting) was &amp;ldquo;deference to authority&amp;rdquo;, and it sounded to me like what was being asked for was compliance.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>